Zheng (Thomas) Tang

APPLIED SCIENTIST, METROPOLIS AT NVIDIA · EXPERT IN COMPUTER VISION AND MACHINE LEARNING

11431 Willows Rd 200, Redmond, WA 98052, USA

🛮 (+1) 206-669-5590 | 🔀 tangzhengthomas@gmail.com | 🏶 zhengthomastang.github.io | 🖸 zhengthomastang | 🗖 zhengthomastang

Summary _

Current Applied Scientist, Metropolis at NVIDIA · Previous Research Scientist, Amazon One at Amazon (2019 - 2021) · Ph.D. in Electrical & Computer Engineering at the University of Washington · 3 filed U.S. patents and 17 publications · Associate Editor of T-CSVT · Organizing Committee member of the AI City Challenge Workshops in CVPR · 9-month internship at NVIDIA with 2 papers accepted to CVPR'19 and ICCV'19 · Leader of the winning team at the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18 · Finalist of 2 Best Student Paper Awards at ICPR'16

Education

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

- Advised by Prof. Jenq-Neng Hwang (IEEE Fellow) at the Information Processing Lab
- Dissertation topic: Robust Video Object Tracking via Camera Self-Calibration

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

• GPA: 3.83/4.0

Sep. 2014 - Mar. 2016

Queen Mary University of London (QMUL)

London, UK

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

· First Class Honours

Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT)

Beijing, China

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

• GPA: 88.73/100

Work Experience_

NVIDIA Redmond, WA, USA

APPLIED SCIENTIST, METROPOLIS

May 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed NVIDIA MDX (Metropolis Data Analytics Toolkit) based on Kafka providing analytics for streaming sensor perception metadata
- Organizing the AI City Challenge Workshops in conjunction with CVPR that have attracted 1,000+ participating teams across 40+ countries

Amazon Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH SCIENTIST, AMAZON ONE

Jul. 2019 - May 2021

- Worked on the research team that developed and launched **Amazon One**, an identity service using people's palm for payment, entry and more
- Invented an architecture that utilized various modalities of sensor data for automated user identification and was filed for a U.S. patent
- Invented a mechanism to update identification data in automated user-identification systems that was also filed for a U.S. patent

NVIDIASanta Clara, CA, USA

INTELLIGENT VIDEO ANALYTICS INTERN

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- Created CityFlow, a city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera (MTMC) vehicle tracking and ReID, accepted to CVPR'19 (Oral)
- · Proposed PAMTRI, a pose-aware multi-task network for vehicle ReID using highly randomized synthetic data, accepted to ICCV'19

University of Washington

Seattle, WA, USA Jun. 2015 - Jun. 2018

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

• Built clustering-based vehicle tracking and camera self-calibration that won in Track 1 of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18

- Developed multi-camera tracking from visual and semantic features that won in Track 3 of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Created a 3D human pose estimator to enable overlaying AR for medical simulation under 6-DoF camera motion (funded by ArchieMD Inc.)
- Proposed evolutionary camera self-calibration from tracking, a finalist of 2 Best Student Paper Awards at ICPR'16 (funded by Prism Skylabs)
- Invented adaptive segmentation and tracking with top accuracy (74.82%) on the NLPR_MCT benchmark (funded by Madrona Venture Group)

Professional Service

IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (T-CSVT)

Remote

ASSOCIATE EDITOR

Jan. 2021 - PRESENT

- · Promptly assigned papers for review and offered decisions that helped reduce decision-making time by 52.5 days compared to 2019
- Provided constructive feedback on the innovation, coverage and quality of papers that helped improve the impact factor (4.133 → 4.685)

Selected Publications

JOURNAL ARTICLE

Online-learning-based human tracking across non-overlapping cameras

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

T-CSVT 28.10 (2018) pp. 2870-2883. 2018

CONFERENCE PAPERS

The 5th AI City Challenge

Milind Naphade, Shuo Wang, David C. Anastasiu, Zheng Tang, Ming-Ching Chang, Xiaodong Yang, Yue Yao, Liang Zheng, Pranamesh Chakraborty, Christian E. Lopez, Anuj Sharma, Qi Feng, Vitaly Ablavsky, Stan Sclaroff

Proc. CVPR Workshops, pp. 4263-4273, 2021, Virtual

PAMTRI: Pose-aware multi-task learning for vehicle re-identification using highly randomized synthetic data

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Stan Birchfield, Jonathan Tremblay, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang *Proc. ICCV*, pp. 211–220, 2019, Seoul, Korea

CityFlow: A city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera vehicle tracking and re-identification

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Ming-Yu Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Stan Birchfield, Shuo Wang, Ratnesh Kumar, David Anastasiu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR, pp. 8797-8806, 2019, Long Beach, CA, USA

Joint multi-view people tracking and pose estimation for 3D scene reconstruction

Zheng Tang, Renshu Gu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. ICME, pp. 1-6, 2018, San Diego, CA, USA

Single-camera and inter-camera vehicle tracking and 3D speed estimation based on fusion of visual and semantic features

Zheng Tang, Gaoang Wang, Hao Xiao, Aotian Zheng, Jeng-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR Workshops, pp. 108-115, 2018, Salt Lake City, UT, USA

Inter-camera tracking based on fully unsupervised online learning

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICIP, pp. 2607-2611, 2017, Beijing, China

Multiple-kernel adaptive segmentation and tracking (MAST) for robust object tracking

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Jen-Hui Chuang

Proc. ICASSP, pp. 1115-1119, 2016, Shanghai, China

Camera self-calibration from tracking of moving persons

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Jen-Hui Chuang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICPR, pp. 260–265, 2016, Cancún, México

Patents

Utilizing Sensor Data for Automated User Identification

Zheng Tang, Prithviraj Banerjee, Manoj Aggarwal, Gerard Medioni

U.S. Patent Application No. 17/209,845 (Pending), 2021

Updating Identification Data in Automated User-Identification Systems

Zheng Tang, Lior Zamir, Prithviraj Banerjee, Manoj Aggarwal, Gerard Medioni, Dilip Kumar

U.S. Patent Application No. 17/361,811 (Pending), 2021

Neural Network System for Object Identification

Zheng Tang, Stan Birchfield, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Milind Naphade, Jonathan Tremblay, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang U.S. Patent Application No. 16/442,375 (Pending), 2019

Honors & Awards _

2019	People's Choice Award, Code for the Kingdom (C4TK) Hackathon	Seattle, WA, USA
2018	Winner of Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake City, UT, USA
2018	Winner of Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake City, UT, USA
2017	Winner of Track 2 (AI City Applications), 1st AI City Challenge Workshop in SmartWorld'17	San Francisco, CA, USA
2016	Finalist IBM Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16	Cancún, México
2016	Finalist Intel Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16	Cancún, México

Skills

ProgrammingPython (expert), C/C++ (expert), Java (expert), JavaScript (proficient), MATLAB (expert), MEX(expert)Frameworks & ToolsPyTorch (expert), TensorFlow (expert), Git (expert), Docker (expert), Kafka (expert), DeepStream (expert)LanguagesEnglish (proficient), Mandarin (native), Cantonese (native), Spanish (elementary)